<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Daveads - Startup</title>
    <subtitle>Dive into the abyss of Daveads!</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://daveads.github.io/categories/startup/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daveads.github.io"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2020-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://daveads.github.io/categories/startup/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Two mind blowing articles i read today</title>
        <published>2020-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daveads.github.io/writing/two-mind-blowing-articles/"/>
        <id>https://daveads.github.io/writing/two-mind-blowing-articles/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://daveads.github.io/writing/two-mind-blowing-articles/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Articles on Startups and Success&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.samaltman.com&#x2F;how-to-be-successful&quot;&gt;How To Be Successful&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;blog.samaltman.com&#x2F;hard-startups&quot;&gt;Hard Startups&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to be successful :&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a different definition of success, irrespective of those beliefs we all do have a specific goal in mind that is to be successful.
Meaning we do all have to put in the hard work, sleepless night and also working smart.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sam altman actually explained, so I won&#x27;t go into full details you can always read the articles.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self belief&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:
Not believing in yourself makes the whole process even &lt;a class=&quot;external&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=gFE-Tdz24hM&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot;&gt;harder&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, this made me remember one of steve job&#x27;s quote..&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;strong&gt;The people who are crazy enough to think they can change the world are the one who do.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning to think independently&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:
There is always a solution to every problem, &lt;strong&gt;success is actually 99% failure and 1% success&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, one thing i learn to do is treat every failed attempt as an experiment or a learning process...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;:&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
This is one of the quality i currently lack, According to Steve Jobs,&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;strong&gt;People think focus means saying yes to the thing you&#x27;ve got to focus on. But that&#x27;s not what it means at all. It means saying no to the hundred other good ideas that there are. You have to pick carefully. I&#x27;m actually as proud of the things we haven&#x27;t done as the things I have done.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;others-i-consider-important&quot;&gt;Others i consider important&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;becoming hard to compete with&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;be bold&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;be internally driven&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taking risks&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;be good at sales&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;build a network&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You get rich by owning things&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;hard-startups&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hard startups&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has a different perspective to this, I like the writer&#x27;s perspective and also belief startup founders should have a long-term commitment. This made me curious &lt;strong&gt;what should startup in developing countries focus on...?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Technological Innovation in developing countries</title>
        <published>2020-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2020-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://daveads.github.io/writing/innovation-in-developing-countries/"/>
        <id>https://daveads.github.io/writing/innovation-in-developing-countries/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://daveads.github.io/writing/innovation-in-developing-countries/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;&#x2F;b&gt; These are based on my views on factors affecting the rate of innovation in developing countries. I might be wrong, but at the same time, I might be right.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing this article feels a little weird for me; it seems like something I should not write about, but I also have the feeling that I should do it anyway. &lt;strong&gt;Keeping this as short as possible, I won&#x27;t be able to cover all areas.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People in developing countries seem to believe that the governing entities are solely responsible for bringing about technological innovation &lt;strong&gt;(this is done indirectly)&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;, which is something I &lt;strong&gt;strongly disagree with&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;. I guess I am not expressing this in the right way; coming from a tech background, there is a lot I don&#x27;t fully understand about politics. It&#x27;s not an excuse, but rather than complaining, that energy should be directed towards something else.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the mindset (culture) and beliefs of the people are really mind-blowing. I love this quote: &lt;cite&gt;&quot;You are what you believe in.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;cite&gt; It&#x27;s really funny how, at the age of 20-25 in most cases, you are still considered incapable of making decisions that could cause a serious change in society, down to individual families, and this becomes a loop.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It makes me wonder what the adults spend their youthful age doing in their 20&#x27;s....???&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt; This makes me want to give examples of Bill Gates, Steve Jobs, Mark Zuckerberg...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To a point, you can&#x27;t entirely blame society for this; many youths spend their time in the most unproductive ways you could ever think of, involving themselves in internet fraud and other criminal activities, etc.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is a lot at play here:&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of knowledge, even in a major field (poor education background, mostly outdated curriculum).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of infrastructure, etc.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technological innovation can be brought about by innovative individuals (Tech Visionaries) who:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;x. See things differently.&lt;br&gt;
x. Have a serious, intense passion for what they do.&lt;br&gt;
x. Are ready to take action no matter the odds.&lt;br&gt;
x. Are tired of doing things the old way (with low outcomes).&lt;br&gt;
x. Are highly curious (question everything) and have the ability to connect the dots.&lt;br&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t get me wrong, one person can&#x27;t actually change the world; you are going to work together with intelligent humans and people who think alike to actually make a mark.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
